<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<resume>

	<!-- Biography -->
	<biography>
		<name>Brad Candell</name>
		<title>Senior Software/Application Architect</title>
		<location>Eau Claire, WI</location>
	</biography>


	<!-- Introductory Statement -->
	<introduction>
		<![CDATA[
		  As a passionate developer, I am always looking to technology to improve
		  the development experience, enhance the quality of my work and improve the way that 
		  users interact with software. I am proud to consistently strive for excellence in 
		  all aspects of my career, with a strong foundation of self-driven, continued learning.
		]]>
	</introduction>


	<!-- Contact Information -->
	<contacts>
		<contact type="email">BradCandell@live.com</contact>
		<contact type="phone">715-559-4794</contact>
		<contact type="twitter">BradCandell</contact>
		<contact type="twitter">ProgrammingHIT</contact>
		<contact type="github">BradCandell</contact>
	</contacts>


	<!-- Experience & Work History -->
	<experience>
		<job title="Senior Software Architect">
			<employer>
				<name>PESI</name>
				<location>
					<address>3839 White Avenue</address>
					<city>Eau Claire</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<zip>54703</zip>
				</location>
			</employer>
			<period>
				<from year="2019" month="5" />
			</period>
			<description>
				At PESI I have been part of a small team working to implement an enterprise-wide business management
				system to support the businesses ongoing initiatives. Taking a cloud-first approach, the entire platform
				is written, managed, tested and built in Microsoft Azure. Since completing the initial research and 
				development, I have begun using my creative skills to lead the frontend development in React/Typescript.
			</description>
		</job>
		<job title="Senior Software Architect">
			<employer>
				<name>Group Health Cooperative of Eau Claire / KMTSJ, Inc.</name>
				<location>
					<address>2503 N. Hillcrest Parkway</address>
					<city>Altoona</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<zip>54720</zip>
				</location>
			</employer>
			<period>
				<from year="2015" month="10" />
				<to year="2019" month="5" />
			</period>
			<description>
				Though my title suggests primarily focusing on software architecture, the continuous needs 
				of the organization led to leveraging my skills in security, analysis, administration and 
				database. I enjoy designing solutions that allow the team to continue to grow and innovate, 
				while maintaining the highest level of performance and reliability. 
			</description>
		</job>

		<job title="Web Developer Lead">
			<employer>
				<name>Group Health Cooperative of Eau Claire / KMTSJ, Inc.</name>
				<location>
					<address>2503 N. Hillcrest Parkway</address>
					<city>Altoona</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<zip>54720</zip>
				</location>
			</employer>
			<period>
				<from year="2012" month="4" />
				<to year="2015" month="10" />
			</period>
			<description>
				Created, maintained and supported four separate public-facing web properties. While my 
				primary focus when hired was on web development, my security and administration background 
				was quickly realized and leveraged in all aspects of the business. I was key in implementing 
				agile, drastic security improvements, virtualization, hiring and much more. 
			</description>
		</job>

		<job title="Application Developer &amp; Architect">
			<employer>
				<name>IDEXX Laboratories</name>
				<location>
					<address>2536 Alpine Rd.</address>
					<city>Eau Claire</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<zip>54703</zip>
				</location>
			</employer>
			<period>
				<from year="2006" month="1" />
				<to year="2012" month="4" />
			</period>
			<description>
				Develop desktop, server, and web applications for both internal and external customers. 
				Specialized in highly scalable applications, web services, and a variety of efficiency improving 
				solutions. I was responsible for the conception and development of several large projects that 
				created efficiency, customer satisfaction, and revenue throughout the organization.
			</description>
		</job>

		<job title="Senior Support Technician">
			<employer>
				<name>IDEXX Laboratories</name>
				<location>
					<address></address>
					<city>Eau Claire</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<zip></zip>
				</location>
			</employer>
			<period>
				<from year="2001" month="9" />
				<to year="2006" month="1" />
			</period>
			<description>
				As a senior support technician, my role is to aide my fellow associates in call escalation, 
				customer satisfaction, and training. I was also very active in the testing phase of both 
				hardware and software additions to the software product for which we supported. During this phase I
				developed several automation tools that increased the efficiency, as well as a dynamic knowledgebase 
				system that is still being utilized today.
			</description>
		</job>

	</experience>

	<!-- Skills -->
	<skills>

		<skill title="Web Development">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="HTML/XHTML" />
			<item title="HTML5" />
			<item title="React" />
			<item title="React Native" />
			<item title="Typescript" />
			<item title="CSS" />
			<item title="SCSS/SASS/LESS" />
			<item title="Javascript" />
			<item title="jQuery" />
			<item title="XML" />
			<item title="XSLT" />
			<item title="JSON" />
			<item title="Bootstrap" />
			<item title="Zurb Foundation" />
			<item title="NodeJS" />
			<item title="Cypress" />
			<item title="Jest" />
			<item title="Storybook" />
		</skill>

		<skill title="Microsoft">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="C#" />
			<item title="Visual Basic &amp; VB.NET" />
			<item title="ASP.NET (WebForms)" />
			<item title="ASP.NET (MVC)" />
			<item title="WPF" />
			<item title="Sharepoint" />
			<item title="Owin" />
			<item title=".Net Core" />
			<item title="Nuget" />
			<item title="Powershell" />
			<item title="MEF" />
			<item title="MSMQ" />
			<item title="F#" />
			<item title="Team Foundation Server (TFS)" />
			<item title="Azure DevOps" />
			<item title="Azure B2C" />
		</skill>

		<skill title="Database">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="Oracle" />
			<item title="Microsoft SQL Server" />
			<item title="Amazon Simple DB" />
			<item title="Microsoft Access" />
			<item title="PostGreSQL" />
			<item title="MySQL" />
			<item title="SyBase" />
			<item title="MongoDB" />
			<item title="SSIS" />
			<item title="SSRS" />
			<item title="Sharepoint" />
		</skill>

		<skill title="System Administration">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="Microsoft Exchange / Office 365" />
			<item title="Active Directory" />
			<item title="Desktop Management" />
			<item title="Virtualization (VMware &amp; Hyper-V)" />
			<item title="Storage (NetApp &amp; Equallogic)" />
			<item title="Mitel Telephony Infrastructure" />
			<item title="System Monitoring with Zabbix" />
			<item title="Operational Automation" />
			<item title="Business Continuity &amp; Disaster Recovery" />
			<item title="High Availability" />
			<item title="Distributed File Systems" />
		</skill>

		<skill title="Security">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="Cisco Email Security Appliance (ESA)" />
			<item title="Firewall Management" />
			<item title="Physical Access Controls (Secura-Key &amp; Infinias)" />
			<item title="Wiegand Interfaces" />
			<item title="Penetration Testing (Metasploit)" />
			<item title="Social Engineering" />
			<item title="X509" />
			<item title="Role Based Access Controls" />
			<item title="OAuth / OpenID / JWT" />
			<item title="PKI" />
			<item title="Bouncy Castle Encryption" />
			<item title="HIPAA" />
			<item title="PCI" />
			<item title="Security &amp; Compliance Staff Education" />
			<item title="Identity &amp; Access Management" />
			<item title="Single Sign-on (SSO)" />

		</skill>

		<skill title="Cloud Technologies">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="Amazon Web Services (AWS)" />
			<item title="Microsoft Azure" />
			<item title="Okta" />
			<item title="Twilio" />
		</skill>

		<skill title="Other">
			<summary>
				<![CDATA[
				]]>
			</summary>
			<item title="Github" />
			<item title="Java" />
			<item title="RabbitMQ / AMQP" />
			<item title="Bash" />
			<item title="Perl" />
			<item title="Multi-Tenancy" />
			<item title="Regular Expressions (Regex)" />
			<item title="Web API Technologies (SOAP/REST)" />
			<item title="SAML" />
			<item title="JWT" />
			<item title="C/C++" />
			<item title="Low Level TCP/IP" />
			<item title="X12 (ASC)" />
			<item title="NCPDP" />
			<item title="PDE" />
			<item title="Markdown" />
			<item title="Near Field Communication (NFC)" />
		</skill>

	</skills>

	<!-- Community Involvement -->
	<community>

		<involvement organization="Shawtown Neighborhood Association" role="President">
			In my role as the President of the (Historic) Shawtown Neighborhood Association, I am responsible for 
			leading a team of 4 Officers and 4 At-Large Members in supporting initiatives that directly support and 
			benefit the neighborhood.
		</involvement>

		<involvement organization="Cub Scouts (Pack 238)" role="Cubmaster">
			I am proud to serve as the Cubmaster of Cub Scout Pack 238 in Eau Claire, WI. As the Cubmaster, I am 
			responsible for	leading the entire Pack into success. With a long history of scouting myself, it was 
			very easy to offer my experience when called upon. I have the privilege of guiding both a leadership 
			team and the scouts themselves into strengthening the skills and values of the scouting organization.
      
			Helping foster a learning, fun Scout-experience for both boy and girl Cub Scouts in the Chippewa Valley. 
			Our Pack/Unit has grown substantially over, boasting one of the largest groups in the area. Helping adults 
			and kids build their leadership and teamwork skills while providing youth with opportunities and experiences 
			that they might not otherwise have access.
		</involvement>

		<involvement organization="That Conference" role="Planning Committee &amp; Registration">
			I have the privilege of being part of the team responsible for holding one of the Midwest's largest 
			developer conference. "That Conference" is held each year in the Wisconsin Dells, and provides ample 
			learning opportunities for over 1200 conference attendees (and their families) to learn about nearly 
			all technologies and platforms. As the conference has grown, the need to specialize has moved me into 
			focusing largely on the registration process at the event. All of the tools to support the conference 
			have been developed internally, and the registration has changed considerably since the first conference.

			I enjoy the (often exhausting) opportunity to talk and/or meet a large number of campers and their 
			families during the registration process and get to know their roles, technological interests and 
			what they are most excited to learn about during the conference.
		</involvement>

		<involvement organization="HIPAA COW (Collaborative of Wisconsin)" role="Planning Committee &amp; Networking Group Co-Chair">
      		After starting in my role at Group Health, I found it surprisingly impossible to locate avenues for IT
			professionals to collaborate on the impact of HIPAA on technology. I quickly found that areas that I
      		thought would be technical (ie. Security) were often more geared to policy and compliance, and less
      		about the technologies that must enforce them.
      		
      		I reached out to the President of the HIPAA COW organization in the hopes of forming a technology-specific
      		networking group that provided a collaborative space for IT technologists to discuss the aspects of the law
      		and how they have met its requirements.
      	
			In addition to my role as the Co-Chair of the HIPAA COW Healthcare IT Networking Group, I am involved in 
			planning each of the bi-annual conferences held throughout the state of Wisconsin. I am proud to have added 
			a completely separate track to the conferences for strictly IT content, which has led to significant growth 
			in conference attendance.
		</involvement>

		<involvement organization="Chippewa Valley Technical College (CVTC)" role="Advisory Chair">
			I have been serving as the "Advisory Committee Chair" for the Chippewa Valley Technical College's IT 
			Software Developer program for nearly 14 years. In my role I am responsible for leading a group of 
			industry representatives in helping the program shape its annual curriculum. Each semester we review 
			the technologies that will be taught and help the college understand the demands we are experiencing 
			within the Chippewa Valley.
		</involvement>

		<involvement organization="Eau Claire Area School District (ECASD)" role="Learning Environments and Partnerships (LEAP) Committee Member">
			The Learning Environments and Partnerships Committee is a standing committee of the ECASD School Board. It was 
			established to &quot;…encourage innovation, which could increase our ability to provide diverse programming and 
			methodologies.&quot; The committee created a three-step process for teachers to have the opportunity to imagine, 
			develop, implement, and interpret an educational program which may not be associated with conventional educational 
			programs. Those programs become part of the District’s Innovation Zone.

			I am enjoying the opportunity to participate as a Parent-member to a committee dedicated to providing innovative ways
			to expose more educational programming to the children of Eau Claire.
		</involvement>
	</community>


	<!-- Education -->
	<education>
		<item type="High School" name="Memorial High School" location="Eau Claire, WI" graduation="1997" />
	</education>


	<!-- Interests and Activities -->
	<interests>
		<interest title="Family (4 children)">
			My wife and I are the proud parents of four wonderful children. Caleb, Grant, Adeline and Grayson. I have
			the added privilege of being able to raise them in the same home in which I was raised. I am most proud of
			the values that I have been gifted from my parents, and the luxury of handing them down to each of my children.
		</interest>
		<interest title="Camping">
			My family and I enjoy frequent camping trips to many of Wisconsin's State Parks. Our favorite
			is Brunet Island State Park (Cornell) and Perrot State Park (Trempealeau).
		</interest>
		<interest title="Fishing">
			My family and I enjoy fishing during all seasons of the year. We usually seek Largemouth Bass,
			Smallmouth Bass, Northern Pike, and panfish. As much fun as I have catching fish myself, I have
			found that helping my children catch fish is even more enjoyable.
		</interest>
		<interest title="Woodworking">
			Having learned the basic skills from my Grandfather as a young boy, I have been woodworking for
			several decades. I have enjoyed building items that vary from small boxes all the way to furniture
			and cabinets. I have always enjoyed learning new and more difficult skills, and take great pride
			in my woodworking shop.
		</interest>
		<interest title="Remodeling">
			I am the proud owner of the home for which I was born and raised. After being built in the 1870's, it is
			certainly somewhat of an antique on its own. Building upon my woodworking skills, I have taught
			myself how to handle most all aspects of remodeling, from plumbing to drywall.
		</interest>
		<interest title="Antique Restoration">
			As an extension of both Woodworking and Remodeling, I have found great joy in restoring various antiques.
			I have restored several Stanley Hand Planes, an antique mahogany dining room table set and recently a
			rare dining room buffet made in 1901. I have also recently purchased an antique sofa/love seat set from
			1875 that may test my ability to learn new skills!
		</interest>
		<interest title="Microcontrollers">
			Starting with the Arduino and Netduino microcontrollers in 2010, I have enjoyed steadily growing
			my experience with small electronics and microcontrollers. As a developer, I have always enjoyed
			the luxury of creating software to do virtually anything. Microcontrollers have provided me with
			the ability to bring software into the physical world. I have recently began learning more about
			the Photon/Particle ecosystem. I have recently begun planning a custom CNC machine that I can leverage
			in my woodworking shop.
		</interest>
	</interests>

</resume>